is it true is Muhammad actually in the
Bible
that's what we're going to be finding
out in our next mathematical challenge
stay tuned
[Music]
hey guys Pastor Myers here and in our
next mathematical challenge we're going
to be dealing with Muhammad in Bible
prophecy so this is called the Muhammad
in the Bible math challenge and we're
going to get right to it so uh if you go
online
go on YouTube and just type in Muhammad
Deuteronomy 18 or Muhammad Isaiah
chapter 42 you will find a lot of
surprising claims and so you will see
videos like this one the Prophet
Muhammad in Isaiah 42 you'll see again
uh um I mean it's it's like kind of all
over the Internet that Muhammad was
prophesied in the Bible particularly in
Isaiah chapter 42 you would also see
reference to Deuteronomy chapter 18
where the Bible speaks of God raising up
a prophet like unto Moses and you'll
even see Malachi chapter 3.
so
and in terms of Malachi chapter 3 we're
talking about the messenger of the
Covenant
so in our challenge today we're going to
be taking a look at this claim and we're
going to apply a math challenge to see
if this claim is actually true so to do
that
we're just going to go ahead and start
with Deuteronomy chapter 18 uh and look
at the context of this Prophet that was
to come on the scene that would be
likened unto Moses so let's go ahead
we're going to begin with Deuteronomy
chapter 18 verse 15 and note what the
Bible says here the Lord thy God will
raise up unto thee a prophet from the
midst of thee of thy Brethren like unto
me unto him yeesha hearken according to
all that thou desired in the of the Lord
thy God in a horrib in the day of the
assembly
saying let me not hear again the voice
of the Lord my God neither let me see
this great fire anymore that I die not
and the Lord said unto me they have well
spoken that which they have spoken I
will raise up a prophet among them among
their Brethren like unto thee and will
put my words in his mouth and he shall
speak unto them all that I shall command
him and it shall come to pass that
whosoever will not hearken unto my words
which he shall speak in my name I will
require it of him so this is the the
scripture that uh Muslims use to teach
that Muhammad was actually prophesied
for various reasons they say that
Muhammad is that Prophet like unto Moses
if you look at the life of Muhammad and
you look at the life of Moses they were
very similar and this is this this is
the the standard that they will use to
say see this is the prophet so let's go
ahead and before we get to Isaiah 42 or
Malachi chapter 3 I just want you to
note here in what way this Prophet was
to be like Moses it's not just in any
way like he'll be a man like Moses he'll
be tall like Moses he'll you know there
are a lot of ways that somebody could be
like Moses but the prophecy is actually
very specific
so let's go ahead and look at
Deuteronomy chapter 5 to see what
happened when the children of Israel
were like don't let God talk to us
what was a context behind God saying I'm
going to raise up another prophet
in Deuteronomy 5 here's what it reads
it says in a came to pass when you heard
the voice out of the midst of the
darkness for the mountain did burn with
fire that you came near unto me even all
the heads of your tribes and your elders
and you said behold the Lord Our God has
showed us his glory and his greatness
and we have heard his voice out of the
midst of the fire and have seen this day
that God does talk with man and he
liveth
now therefore why should we die for this
great fire will consume us if we hear
the voice of the Lord Our God anymore
then we shall die so they are terrified
of God they don't want to hear his voice
anymore
uh Deuteronomy 5 26 for all for who is
there of All Flesh that has heard the
voice of the Living God speaking out of
the midst of the fire as we have and
lived now notice the next verse verse 27
go thou near and hear all that the Lord
Our God shall say and speak thou unto us
all that the Lord Our God shall speak
unto thee and we will hear it and do it
so what are they asking Moses to be here
they're asking him to be a mediator
a mediate our soul
notice the next verse verse 28 and the
Lord heard the voice of your words when
you speak unto me and the Lord said unto
me I have heard the voice of the words
of these people which they have spoken
unto thee they have well said all that
they have spoken this is exactly what's
quoted in Deuteronomy chapter 18. so
please note
that
the way that this other Prophet was to
be like Moses was to be a mediator
one that would stand between God and the
people now it doesn't end there
um because we're gonna see
in Exodus 24 what Moses did as the
mediator
so notice with me Exodus 24 verse 1 and
he said unto Moses come up unto the Lord
thou and Aaron and Bahu and 70 of the
Elders of Israel and Worship You far off
and Moses alone shall come near the Lord
but they shall not come nigh neither
shall the people go up with him and
Moses came and told the people all the
words of the Lord
and all the judgments and all the people
answered with one voice and said all the
words which the Lord has said we will do
and Moses wrote all the words of the
Lord and Rose up early in the morning
and built an altar under the hill and 12
pillars according to the 12 tribes of
Israel so there's an agreement Happening
Here There is a covenant Happening Here
and what we're going to see is that
Moses
stood as the mediator of this Covenant
this is the way that the prophet like
unto Moses is to be compared in other
words
what is the thing that set aside Moses
from all the other prophets that came
after him being Jeremiah Think Isaiah
none of those prophets served as a
mediator between God and man none of
those prophets
confirmed a covenant between God and the
people only Moses did
so we can compare all the other prophets
and say hey like Moses Jeremiah did this
like Moses Isaiah did this right they
prophesied and and there are various
ways we can say that all the prophets
are alike but Moses is the only Prophet
that served
as one to confirm a covenant between God
and man
let's go to Exodus 24 verse 5 just to
verify this point
Bible says here
and he sent young men of the children of
Israel which offered burnt offerings and
sacrifice peace offerings of of oxen
unto the Lord and Moses took half of the
blood and put it in basins and half of
the blood he sprinkled on the altar
and he took the book of the Covenant and
read in the audience of the people and
they said all that the Lord has said we
will do and be obedient and Moses took
the blood and sprinkled it on the people
and said behold the blood of the
Covenant which the Lord has made with
you concerning all these words so Moses
confirmed the Covenant between God and
the people and this is the way in which
the prophet like unto Moses must be
compared this is how the prophet is to
be compared
all right
so with that in mind
we can now begin to see
a pattern when we go to the book of
Isaiah which is the next place that
Muslims say here is Muhammad the Bible
is prophesying Muhammad all right we're
getting to the math challenge this is
not going to be long at all we're just
setting the foundation and we're going
to see the Snapchat is going to be very
simple if this is really talking about
Muhammad
there is a mathematic equation to prove
this
okay so Isaiah 42.
the Bible says in verse 1 behold my
servant whom I uphold mine elect in whom
my soul delighteth I have put my spirit
upon him he saw bring forth judgment to
the Gentiles he shall not cry nor lift
up nor cause his voice to be heard in
the street
a bruise read shutting not break and the
smoking flag shall he not quench he
shall bring forth judgment unto truth he
shall not fail nor be discouraged so he
has set judgment in the earth and the
Isle shall wait for his law
verse 5 thus say the Lord God
he that created the heavens and
stretched them out he that spread forth
the Earth and that which cometh out of
it he that giveth bread unto or breath
unto the people on upon it and spirit to
them that walk therein now watch verse
6.
I the Lord have called thee in
righteousness and will hold thine hand
and will keep thee and give thee for a
covenant of the people for a light to
the Gentiles to open the blind eyes to
bring out the prisoner from the prison
and then that sin in darkness out of the
prison house so again
in Isaiah 42 you see this parallel
dealing with the Covenant whoever this
is will have a role to play in The
Covenant for the people
are you following
Deuteronomy 18
reveals to us that Moses
uh the The Profit that would come like
Moses is pointing to the fact that Moses
confirmed a covenant between God and the
people and now we see the same thing
here in Isaiah 42.
he's going to have something to do with
confirming the Covenant for the people
in fact we we see this same phrase in
Isaiah 49 verse 8 thus saith the Lord in
an acceptable time have I heard thee and
in a day of salvation have I helped thee
and I will preserve thee and give thee
for a covenant of the people
to establish the Earth to cause to
inherit the desolate Heritage heritages
that thou mayest say to the prisoners go
forth to them that are in darkness show
yourselves they shall feed in thy ways
in the ways and their pastors shall be
in all high places so again
we see this parallel
that whoever this Prophet is
is going to play a role in confirming
the Covenant of the people okay
now let's go to the Book of Malachi and
guess what you're going to see this is
the same place Malachi chapter three one
of the other places that Muslims say ah
this is speaking about Muhammad notice
what it says in Malachi 3 verse 1 behold
I will send my messenger and he shall
prepare the way before me and the Lord
whom you seek shall suddenly come to his
Temple even the messenger of the
Covenant whom you Delight in behold he
shall come say the Lord of hosts so
once again
the the three verses that Muslims point
to as speaking about Muhammad all have
to do
with the messenger of the Covenant
the one who confirms the Covenant
the one who mediates the Covenant
Isaiah didn't mediate a covenant
Jeremiah did mediate a covenant no other
prophet in the Old Testament did what
Moses did and so whoever this Prophet is
he must be unique in that way
there are a thousand different ways to
compare he will be a man like Moses he
will he might be tall like Moses he
might be the same complexion as Moses we
can make up all kinds of things that
would say see he was like Moses in this
way in this way in this way and this way
no the thing that set Moses aside from
every other prophet in the Old Testament
is that Moses was the mediator of the
Covenant
now with that in mind
we're about to go to our math challenge
because what most Muslims may be unaware
of is that this same individual that
would confirm the Covenant is actually
spoken of in the Book of Daniel chapter
9.
and there is a mathematic equation
connected to the timing of his appearing
so let's read it
Daniel chapter 9 verse 24. the Bible
says here 70 weeks and that is the math
equation we're going to be looking at at
least the math challenge that I will be
presenting
70 weeks are determined upon thy people
and upon thy Holy City to finish a
transgression to make an end of sins to
make reconciliation for iniquity to
bring an everlasting righteousness to
seal up the vision in Prophecy and to
anoint the most holy now this word most
holy is pointing to the sanctuary please
note
that back in Malachi 3 it said that this
messenger
would come to the temple would come to
the temple and lo and behold we see in
Daniel 9 that there is an individual
that is coming there is something that's
going to happen that's going to to lead
to the anointing of the temple let's
keep reading
know therefore and understand that from
the going forth of the Commandment to
restore and to build Jerusalem unto the
Messiah the prince shall be seven weeks
and three score in two weeks the streets
shall be built again and the walls even
in trouble as times and now here's what
I want to focus on and after three score
in two weeks some side being cut off but
not for himself and the people of the
prince at shall come shall destroy the
city and the sanctuary and the end there
of Sabi with a flood and unto the end of
the war desolations are determined
here's what we're going to focus on here
is a challenge
in verse 27 it says and he shall confirm
the Covenant
stop for a second
whoever this he is
it is the same he
as the he and Malachi 3. the messenger
of the Covenant
it is the same he
as the one found in Isaiah 42 I will
give thee for a covenant to the people
the Gentiles
it is the same he that is found in
Deuteronomy 18 I will raise up a prophet
like unto thee Moses who did what
confirmed a covenant
and so so look at what it says he shall
confirm the Covenant with many for one
week and in the midst of the week he
shall cause the sacrifice and the
oblations to cease and for the
overspreading of Abominations he shall
make it desolate even until the
consummation and that determined shall
be poured upon the desolate so here is
the math challenge look nice and short
we're under 20 minutes and we're done
here is the math challenge for Muslims
demonstrates
how this
70-week prophecy is connected to the
Prophet Muhammad
because this 70-week prophecy
pinpoints the time that the prophet like
unto Moses in Deuteronomy 18 in Isaiah
42 and in Malachi 3 all the same
individual it pinpoints the time of his
arrival
it is sometime within this 70-week
period so the challenge for Muslims is
to present how Muhammad fits the con the
prophet or the person who was to confirm
the Covenant
in this prophecy
you see it's easy to just throw anybody
in there and say well in fact I don't
know if you realize this but Mormons
teach that the Prophet Joseph Smith is
the prophet of Deuteronomy 18 that was
to be like unto Moses
so you can take anybody and try to make
them fit and they go into all details
about how uh uh Joseph Smith was like
Moses in this way in this way in this
way and this way the problem is beloved
that the way in which the prophet is to
be like Moses
is in confirming a covenant between God
and the people
and there is a time element
pinpointing the his arrival
unless you can demonstrate how Muhammad
fits that mathematic that time stamp
that math equation then
plain and simple Muhammad is not that
prophet
so there's your challenge
create a video do whatever you need to
do
respond in this uh in the comments below
but demonstrate to us
how Muhammad fulfills this 70-week
prophecy and if he doesn't
who does
all right I look forward to your answers
may God bless you
as you search for truth
[Music]